<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <rdf:Description>
      <dc:title>The Philippines: Past and Present (Volume 2 of 2)</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Dean Conant Worcester (1866–1924)</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Project Gutenberg, Urbana, Illinois, USA., 2013-01-26</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2013-01-26</dc:date>
      <dc:rights>This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online at www.gutenberg.org.
This eBook is produced by the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at www.pgdp.net.
The author, Dean C. Worcester, was a member of the Philippine Commission and afterwards Secretary of the Interior for the Insular Government of the Philippine Islands. In this work he gives an impression of the early years of American colonial politics in the Philippines, which the US acquired in 1898. It goes into a lot of detail on the dealings with the Filipino resistance, the organization of the administration, education, health-service, etc. Probably the most controversial of all American officials during the American era, considerable space is dedicated to rebutting the strong criticism in James H. Blount’s The American Occupation of the Philippines, 1898–1912.
Volume I of this work is also available from Project Gutenberg.
Scans of this work are available from the Internet Archive (Volume I, copy 1, 2; Volume II, copy 1, 2, 3).
</dc:rights>
      <dc:subject>Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Philippines</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>The author, Dean C. Worcester, was a member of the Philippine Commission and afterwards Secretary of the Interior for the Insular Government of the Philippine Islands. In this work he gives an impression of the early years of American colonial politics in the Philippines, which the US acquired in 1898. It goes into a lot of detail on the dealings with the Filipino resistance, the organization of the administration, education, health-service, etc. Probably the most controversial of all American officials during the American era, considerable space is dedicated to rebutting the strong criticism in James H. Blount’s The American Occupation of the Philippines, 1898–1912.</dc:description>
      <dc:identifier>pg:41918</dc:identifier>
   </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>